[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "Processed data is called:",
    "options": ["Value", "Information", "Summary", "Program"],
    "answer": "Information"
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "Scanner is a ___ device.",
    "options": ["primary memory", "output", "input", "secondary memory"],
    "answer": "input"
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "Difference between compiler and interpreter is:",
    "options": [
      "Compiler checks the code as a whole and interpreter checks line by line of the code",
      "Interpreter checks the code as a whole and compiler checks line by line of the code",
      "Compiler used to find syntax errors while interpreter used to find run time error",
      "Interpreter used to find syntax errors while compiler used to find run time error"
    ],
    "answer": "Compiler checks the code as a whole and interpreter checks line by line of the code"
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "Example of operating system:",
    "options": ["Microsoft XP", "Microsoft office", "Adobe reader", "Adobe page maker"],
    "answer": "Microsoft XP"
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "___ is a volatile memory.",
    "options": ["Hard disk", "DVD", "CD", "RAM"],
    "answer": "RAM"
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "Mouse was invented by:",
    "options": ["Charles Babbage", "Douglas Engelbart", "Alan Turing", "John McCarthy"],
    "answer": "Douglas Engelbart"
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "Input device used to read cheques in banks:",
    "options": ["MICR", "OCR", "OMR", "barcode reader"],
    "answer": "MICR"
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "CD is:",
    "options": ["Combined Disk", "Cosmetic Disk", "Casual Disk", "Compact Disk"],
    "answer": "Compact Disk"
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "Example of output device:",
    "options": ["Microphone", "Plotter", "Joy stick", "Light pen"],
    "answer": "Plotter"
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "LCD is:",
    "options": [
      "Liquid Crystal Display",
      "Liberal Circuit Display",
      "Light Crystal Display",
      "Light Circuit Display"
    ],
    "answer": "Liquid Crystal Display"
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "Example for secondary memory:",
    "options": ["RAM", "ROM", "CD", "All the above"],
    "answer": "CD"
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "___ is a system software.",
    "options": ["Operating system", "Microsoft word", "PROM", "DRAM"],
    "answer": "Operating system"
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "Debugging is the process of:",
    "options": [
      "finding errors",
      "converting source code to machine code",
      "writing code in a language",
      "Converting source code to assembly language"
    ],
    "answer": "finding errors"
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "Example for machine language:",
    "options": ["Assembly language", "Binary language", "LOTUS", "BASIC"],
    "answer": "Binary language"
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "Example for application software:",
    "options": ["Linux", "Interpreter", "Assembler", "Microsoft excel"],
    "answer": "Microsoft excel"
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "In hexadecimal number system, 'E' stands for:",
    "options": ["5", "14", "2", "15"],
    "answer": "14"
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "The last number in octal number system is:",
    "options": ["7", "8", "9", "10"],
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "number": 18,
    "question": "The base of the number system is:",
    "options": [
      "The number of digits in the number system",
      "The last number of number system",
      "The first number of number system",
      "The sum of digits of number system"
    ],
    "answer": "The number of digits in the number system"
  },
  {
    "number": 19,
    "question": "DTP is:",
    "options": [
      "Digital Text Printing",
      "Display Text Printing",
      "Desktop Publishing",
      "Display Text Publishing"
    ],
    "answer": "Desktop Publishing"
  },
  {
    "number": 20,
    "question": "Define latency time:",
    "options": [
      "Time required to find track",
      "Time required to find sector",
      "Total time required to find the data",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Time required to find sector"
  },
  {
    "number": 21,
    "question": "The binary number corresponding to 5:",
    "options": ["101", "05", "100", "01001"],
    "answer": "101"
  },
  {
    "number": 22,
    "question": "654(8) is a number in ___ number system:",
    "options": ["binary", "octal", "decimal", "hexadecimal"],
    "answer": "octal"
  },
  {
    "number": 23,
    "question": "In sign magnitude form, sign of the number is represented on:",
    "options": ["MSB", "LSB", "MDN", "LDN"],
    "answer": "MSB"
  },
  {
    "number": 24,
    "question": "One's complement of 1001 is:",
    "options": ["1001", "1000", "0101", "0110"],
    "answer": "0110"
  },
  {
    "number": 25,
    "question": "2's complement is calculated by:",
    "options": [
      "Adding 1 to one's complement",
      "Adding 2 to one's complement",
      "Adding 1 to its binary equivalent",
      "Adding 2 to its binary equivalent"
    ],
    "answer": "Adding 1 to one's complement"
  },
  {
    "number": 26,
    "question": "Find the decimal equivalent of 1010101:",
    "options": ["75", "85", "1010101", "101010"],
    "answer": "85"
  },
  {
    "number": 27,
    "question": "The symbol used for input/output operations in flow chart:",
    "options": ["Rectangle", "Parallelogram", "Rhombus", "Oval shape"],
    "answer": "Parallelogram"
  },
  {
    "number": 28,
    "question": "What is topology in computer network?",
    "options": [
      "Arrangement of system in network",
      "Number of system in network",
      "Position of server in network",
      "Area covered by the network"
    ],
    "answer": "Arrangement of system in network"
  },
  {
    "number": 29,
    "question": "Define nodes in network:",
    "options": ["Server", "Systems", "Type of protocol", "Type of connection"],
    "answer": "Systems"
  },
  {
    "number": 30,
    "question": "Expansion of TCP/IP is:",
    "options": [
      "Transport Control Protocol/Internet Protocol",
      "Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol",
      "Transport Control Protocol/Intranet Protocol",
      "Transmission Control Protocol/Intranet Protocol"
    ],
    "answer": "Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol"
  },
  {
    "number": 31,
    "question": "Booting is the process of:",
    "options": [
      "Detecting hardware connected to PC",
      "Loading OS on the PC",
      "Scanning the system for VIRUS",
      "Installing new software in the system"
    ],
    "answer": "Loading OS on the PC"
  },
  {
    "number": 32,
    "question": "Example for a basic gate:",
    "options": ["OR", "XOR", "NOR", "NAND"],
    "answer": "OR"
  },
  {
    "number": 33,
    "question": "How can we make a NAND gate?",
    "options": [
      "Using AND, OR & NOT",
      "Using AND & NOT",
      "Using NOR & AND",
      "Using NOR, AND & OR"
    ],
    "answer": "Using AND & NOT"
  },
  {
    "number": 34,
    "question": "Truth table of OR will give:",
    "options": [
      "True value for all possible inputs",
      "True value when both the inputs are true",
      "True value when anyone of the inputs are true",
      "True value when both the inputs are false"
    ],
    "answer": "True value when anyone of the inputs are true"
  },
  {
    "number": 35,
    "question": "Which one of the following cannot be used as an identifier in C++?",
    "options": ["name", "name123", "break", "break_123"],
    "answer": "break"
  },
  {
    "number": 36,
    "question": "How many bytes of memory is needed to save a float variable?",
    "options": ["8", "4", "2", "16"],
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "number": 37,
    "question": "If you have to execute different lines of code for different choices of a particular variable. Which one of the following control statements will you use?",
    "options": ["for", "while", "do .... while", "switch"],
    "answer": "switch"
  },
  {
    "number": 38,
    "question": "Which one of the following is exit controlled loop?",
    "options": ["for", "while", "do .... while", "switch"],
    "answer": "do .... while"
  },
  {
    "number": 39,
    "question": "for (i = 5; i >1; i -- ) { cout << i; } What will be the output of the program?",
    "options": ["54321", "5432", "12345", "Syntax error"],
    "answer": "5432"
  },
  {
    "number": 40,
    "question": "int i= 6, j=7,k; k = i++ + -- j; cout << k << i << j; What will be the output?",
    "options": ["12 7 6", "13 7 6", "13 6 7", "12 6 6"],
    "answer": "12 7 6"
  },
  {
    "number": 41,
    "question": "Which one of the following is unary operator?",
    "options": ["*", "+", "-", "All the above"],
    "answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "number": 42,
    "question": "By default class variables are:",
    "options": ["Private", "Public", "Protected", "All the above"],
    "answer": "Private"
  },
  {
    "number": 43,
    "question": "Class type variables are called as:",
    "options": ["Member variable", "Private variable", "Object", "Constructor"],
    "answer": "Member variable"
  },
  {
    "number": 44,
    "question": "Specialty of constructor is:",
    "options": [
      "Its name is same as class name",
      "It will not have a return type",
      "It can be overloaded",
      "All the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "number": 45,
    "question": "Collection of variables of same datatype is:",
    "options": ["array", "structure", "object", "loop"],
    "answer": "array"
  },
  {
    "number": 46,
    "question": "Free store operators in C++ are:",
    "options": ["+ & -", "new & delete", "* & /", "array & structure"],
    "answer": "new & delete"
  },
  {
    "number": 47,
    "question": "Why we use scope resolution operator?",
    "options": [
      "To define a structure inside a class",
      "To define a function outside the class",
      "To define an array inside the class",
      "To define a class outside the class"
    ],
    "answer": "To define a function outside the class"
  },
  {
    "number": 48,
    "question": "Which operator will you use to access members of structure using structure variable?",
    "options": ["dot operator", "arrow operator", "underscore", "hyphen"],
    "answer": "dot operator"
  },
  {
    "number": 49,
    "question": "Syntax of declaring an object of a class in C++:",
    "options": [
      "class_name object_name;",
      "class_name object_name=new class_name;",
      "class_name object_name= new class_name ();",
      "class_name object_name=class_name ();"
    ],
    "answer": "class_name object_name;"
  },
  {
    "number": 50,
    "question": "A constructor is called when:",
    "options": [
      "we call the constructor using object of the class",
      "the object of the class is created",
      "a member function is called",
      "we define the constructor"
    ],
    "answer": "the object of the class is created"
  },
  {
    "number": 51,
    "question": "Encapsulation is implemented in C++ using:",
    "options": ["structure", "class", "array", "function"],
    "answer": "class"
  },
  {
    "number": 52,
    "question": "Which symbol is used for commenting in C++?",
    "options": ["//", "/* */", "!", "Both (A) and (B)"],
    "answer": "Both (A) and (B)"
  },
  {
    "number": 53,
    "question": "Define function overloading:",
    "options": [
      "same signature with different function name",
      "same function name with same parameter list",
      "same return type with different function name",
      "same function name with different signature"
    ],
    "answer": "same function name with different signature"
  },
  {
    "number": 54,
    "question": "Which one of the following is multiple inheritance?",
    "options": [
      "A child class derived from another child of a parent class",
      "A parent with more than one child",
      "A child with more than one parent",
      "More than one type of inheritance is included"
    ],
    "answer": "A child with more than one parent"
  },
  {
    "number": 55,
    "question": "int *p, k=5; p=&k; If p is having the value 100. What will be the output of the following code: cout << *p;",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "100",
      "The value saved at the memory location 5",
      "The value saved at the memory location 100"
    ],
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "number": 56,
    "question": "Java is ___ language:",
    "options": ["Compiled", "Interpreted", "Both (A) and (B)", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "Both (A) and (B)"
  },
  {
    "number": 57,
    "question": "Expansion of JVM:",
    "options": [
      "Java Virtual Machine",
      "Java Vigilant Mechanism",
      "Java Virtual Mechanism",
      "Java Vigilant Machine"
    ],
    "answer": "Java Virtual Machine"
  },
  {
    "number": 58,
    "question": "Specialty of main function in java is:",
    "options": ["Public", "Static", "Void", "All the above"],
    "answer": "All the above"
  },
  {
    "number": 59,
    "question": "If we declare 4 objects of a class. How many copies of static variable can be produced:",
    "options": ["3", "2", "1", "4"],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "number": 60,
    "question": "How runtime error in Java is handled?",
    "options": [
      "Using new and delete operator",
      "Using constructor and destructor method",
      "Using try ....... catch method",
      "Using JVM"
    ],
    "answer": "Using try ....... catch method"
  },
  {
    "number": 61,
    "question": "Which datatype is used to declare a variable for saving single alphabet in C++?",
    "options": ["string", "letter", "char", "word"],
    "answer": "char"
  },
  {
    "number": 62,
    "question": "Which keyword is used to include packages in Java?",
    "options": ["include", "initiate", "implements", "import"],
    "answer": "import"
  },
  {
    "number": 63,
    "question": "How multiple inheritance is introduced in Java?",
    "options": ["Using packages", "Using class", "Using utilities", "Using interfaces"],
    "answer": "Using interfaces"
  },
  {
    "number": 64,
    "question": "Which one of the following is used to find remainder in VB?",
    "options": ["%", "\\", "/", "Mod"],
    "answer": "Mod"
  },
  {
    "number": 65,
    "question": "Difference between applet and simple java program is:",
    "options": [
      "Applet program is not compiled",
      "Applets are not written in java",
      "In applet program packages cannot be used",
      "Applet program will not have a main function"
    ],
    "answer": "Applet program will not have a main function"
  },
  {
    "number": 66,
    "question": "How integer variables are declared in VB?",
    "options": ["int a;", "declare a as integer", "dim a as Integer", "a is integer"],
    "answer": "dim a as Integer"
  },
  {
    "number": 67,
    "question": "In VB which window will help you in viewing the position of the form in the main window?",
    "options": ["Properties window", "Position window", "Project Window", "Layout window"],
    "answer": "Layout window"
  },
  {
    "number": 68,
    "question": "The keyword used to declare constant value is:",
    "options": ["Constant", "Cons", "Con", "Const"],
    "answer": "Const"
  },
  {
    "number": 69,
    "question": "In C++, a string constant always ends with:",
    "options": ["%", "/", "\\0", "_"],
    "answer": "\\0"
  },
  {
    "number": 70,
    "question": "___ mode helps to open file in input mode.",
    "options": ["file : input", "open :: input", "ios :: in", "mode :: in"],
    "answer": "ios :: in"
  },
  {
    "number": 71,
    "question": "A function calling itself is called ___ function.",
    "options": ["Recalling", "Reusing", "Redundancy", "Recursive"],
    "answer": "Recursive"
  },
  {
    "number": 72,
    "question": "Which one of the following is not a DML command?",
    "options": ["Delete from", "Insert into", "Alter", "Update"],
    "answer": "Alter"
  },
  {
    "number": 73,
    "question": "Expansion of SDLC:",
    "options": [
      "System Demonstration in Last Cycle",
      "Series Demonstration in Last Cycle",
      "Series Development Life Cycle",
      "System Development Life Cycle"
    ],
    "answer": "System Development Life Cycle"
  },
  {
    "number": 74,
    "question": "Which query will you use to remove a table from db?",
    "options": ["delete from", "truncate", "drop", "remove"],
    "answer": "drop"
  },
  {
    "number": 75,
    "question": "What is tuple in dbms?",
    "options": ["Number of tables", "Number of columns", "Number of rows", "Number of database"],
    "answer": "Number of rows"
  },
  {
    "number": 76,
    "question": "Foreign key is:",
    "options": [
      "Primary key of another table",
      "Primary key of the same table",
      "Any column other than primary key of another table",
      "Any column other than primary key of same table"
    ],
    "answer": "Primary key of another table"
  },
  {
    "number": 77,
    "question": "The command used to add a column in a table:",
    "options": ["Insert into", "Update", "Alter", "Add"],
    "answer": "Alter"
  },
  {
    "number": 78,
    "question": "In SQL, which command is used to make permanent changes made by statements in transaction?",
    "options": ["SAVE", "EXIT", "DONE", "COMMIT"],
    "answer": "COMMIT"
  },
  {
    "number": 79,
    "question": "The PROJECT command will create new table that has:",
    "options": [
      "The selected rows of the parent table",
      "The selected columns of parent table",
      "The selected datatype of the parent table",
      "The selected size of the columns"
    ],
    "answer": "The selected columns of parent table"
  },
  {
    "number": 80,
    "question": "In a ___ a parent record type can be linked to one or more \"child\" record types, but a child record type can have only one parent:",
    "options": [
      "Network database",
      "Relational database",
      "Distributed database",
      "Hierarchical database"
    ],
    "answer": "Hierarchical database"
  },
  {
    "number": 81,
    "question": "The Schenduruney wildlife sanctuary is in:",
    "options": ["Ezhimala", "Thenmala", "Aralam", "Thekkadi"],
    "answer": "Thenmala"
  },
  {
    "number": 82,
    "question": "The Indian origin mathematician who won prestigious global prize 'Fields medal' known as Nobel Prize in mathematics:",
    "options": ["Manjul Bhargava", "Viswanath Chopra", "Kishore Varma", "Anandha Moorthy"],
    "answer": "Manjul Bhargava"
  },
  {
    "number": 83,
    "question": "The Asian country which host the FIFA world cup of 2022:",
    "options": ["Saudi Arabia", "Qatar", "Italy", "Australia"],
    "answer": "Qatar"
  },
  {
    "number": 84,
    "question": "A scheme started by the Central Government to provide food to senior citizens who cannot care for themselves:",
    "options": ["Annadan", "Operation food supply", "Operation oldman", "Annapurna"],
    "answer": "Annapurna"
  },
  {
    "number": 85,
    "question": "Among the names of four nationalists given below, the one who born in Maharastra:",
    "options": ["Gopala Krishna Gokhale", "Annie Beasant", "Nehru", "Lala Lajpath Rai"],
    "answer": "Gopala Krishna Gokhale"
  },
  {
    "number": 86,
    "question": "The footballer who scored maximum number of goals in the world cups:",
    "options": ["Lionel Messi", "Diego Maradona", "Microslave Kloose", "Yorgan Klinsman"],
    "answer": "Microslave Kloose"
  },
  {
    "number": 87,
    "question": "'Sarvodaya movement' is related with:",
    "options": ["Justice Ranade", "Acharya Vinobha Bhave", "Jayaprakash Narayanan", "A.K. Antony"],
    "answer": "Acharya Vinobha Bhave"
  },
  {
    "number": 88,
    "question": "The mountain ranges that separate south India from North India:",
    "options": ["Western Ghatt", "Vindya - Satpura", "Himalaya", "Sabarimala"],
    "answer": "Vindya - Satpura"
  },
  {
    "number": 89,
    "question": "The 20th Common Wealth games held in 'Glasco' recently. Where is it?",
    "options": ["Scotland", "England", "Holland", "Spain"],
    "answer": "Scotland"
  },
  {
    "number": 90,
    "question": "The third oldest football tournament in the world is in India:",
    "options": ["Federation cup", "Nehru Trophy", "Durant cup", "Swaraj Trophy"],
    "answer": "Durant cup"
  },
  {
    "number": 91,
    "question": "The period of 12th Five Year Plan in India:",
    "options": ["1982-1987", "2007-2012", "2002-2007", "2012-2017"],
    "answer": "2012-2017"
  },
  {
    "number": 92,
    "question": "'Chotta Nagpur plateau' in India is on the:",
    "options": ["North", "West", "South", "East"],
    "answer": "East"
  },
  {
    "number": 93,
    "question": "Among the following the name of Mannath Padmanabhan is related with:",
    "options": ["Yokashema Sabha", "Nair Service Society", "Atmiya Sabha", "Sree Narayana Yogam"],
    "answer": "Nair Service Society"
  },
  {
    "number": 94,
    "question": "Gandhiji's autobiography 'My experiments with truth' first published in:",
    "options": ["Gujarati", "Bengali", "Malayalam", "Marathi"],
    "answer": "Gujarati"
  },
  {
    "number": 95,
    "question": "Nagaland produced a brave heroine during the Civil Disobedience movement called:",
    "options": ["Rani Lakshmi Bai", "Ishom Sharma", "Captain Lakshmi", "Rani Gaidiliu"],
    "answer": "Rani Gaidiliu"
  },
  {
    "number": 96,
    "question": "The propounder of the theory that 'Ananda' [happiness] should be the touch stone of any human activity:",
    "options": [
      "Kumara Guru",
      "Swami Sradhanandha",
      "Brahmanand Swami Siva Yogi",
      "Sankaracharya"
    ],
    "answer": "Brahmanand Swami Siva Yogi"
  },
  {
    "number": 97,
    "question": "The place 'Chembazhanthi' is connected with the reformer:",
    "options": ["Kumaranasan", "Sree Narayana Guru", "Ayyankali", "Ramaswami Naikar"],
    "answer": "Sree Narayana Guru"
  },
  {
    "number": 98,
    "question": "U.N.O. observes October 2nd as:",
    "options": [
      "U.N. Day",
      "International Service Day",
      "Gandhi's Birthday",
      "International Non-Violence Day"
    ],
    "answer": "International Non-Violence Day"
  },
  {
    "number": 99,
    "question": "The Great Yogi, who was the Guru of Sri Narayana Guru, Chattampi Swamikal and Ayyankali:",
    "options": [
      "Thycaud Ayya Swamikal",
      "Vagbadananda",
      "Jyothirao Phule",
      "Periyar Swamikal"
    ],
    "answer": "Thycaud Ayya Swamikal"
  },
  {
    "number": 100,
    "question": "The autobiography of former foreign minister Natwar Singh which attained popular attention recently:",
    "options": [
      "Vulgarness of politics",
      "The Broken Wings",
      "One Life is Not Enough",
      "My struggles"
    ],
    "answer": "One Life is Not Enough"
  }
]